Graphing a system of equations has
steps similar to graphing one equation.
Here is a system of two equations.
Y equals four x minus four and
Y equals negative two x plus eight.
First, find the slope and Y
intercept of the first equation.
The slope is four because that is the coefficient of x.
The Y intercept or B is negative four.
Next, find the slope and Y
intercept of the second equation.
The slope is negative two because
that is the coefficient of x.
The Y intercept or b is eight.
Graph both equations on the same coordinate plane.
Remember to first graph the Y intercept.
Then use the slope to find more points.
The first line is the purple line.
The second line is in black.
Identify the solution by finding
where the two lines intersect.
They intersect at the point of 2,4.