Write the equation y equals one third
X minus four in standard form.
The given equation is in slope intercept form.
Remember that was Y equals MX plus B.
Standard form is ax plus by equals C.
Step one: get rid of the fractions in the equation.
Multiply every term by three.
Three Y equals three times the quantity
of one third x minus four.
Step two: distribute and simplify
three Y equals X minus twelve.
Step three: bring the x term to
the same side as the y term.
Subtract x from both sides.
Three Y minus X equals X minus X minus twelve.
Step four: simplify three y
minus X equals negative twelve.
Notice the y term is first.
Step five: write the equation so the x term is first.
Negative x plus three y equals negative twelve.
The problem is now that the
x is negative. In standard form
do not lead with a negative number.
Step six: multiply each term by negative one so
as not to lead with a negative. Negative one
times the quantity of negative x plus three y
equals negative twelve becomes x minus three
Y equals twelve.