When writing an equation from a table of values, you
need two things the y intercept and the slope.
Let's take a look at question six from the activity.
The y intercept is where x equals zero.
To find this, work backward.
Since the pattern of the y value goes up by two,
subtract two to find the value when X equals zero.
When x equals zero, y also equals zero.
Now that the Y intercept is known,
it's time to find the slope.
Remember, slope is the change in
y over the change in x.
Look at the table and find the
change in y and change in x.
Notice that the x values change by one.
The y values change by two.
So the slope is two over one or two.
Now put this all together to write
an equation in slope intercept form.
Slope intercept form is y equals MX plus
B m is the slope, which is two.
B is the y intercept which is zero.
So the equation is y equals two x
plus zero, or y equals two x.
Now it's your turn to try to write
an equation from a table of values.